<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>News-All</title>
        <link>https://www.farms.com/news/</link>
        <description>News-All related content provided by https://www.farms.com/</description>
        <copyright>Copyright © 1995-2026 Farms.com, Ltd. All Rights Reserved.</copyright>

        <item>
            <title>Andrew Coyne: Canada’s Productivity Crisis is Now a National Security Issue</title>
            <link>https://www.farms.com/news/andrew-coyne-canada-s-productivity-crisis-is-now-a-national-security-issue-237793.aspx</link>
            <guid>NEWS_237793</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 17:30:26 GMT</pubDate>
            <description>At the CrossRoads Crop Conference, the Globe and Mail columnist said slowing growth, aging demographics, and weak competition leave Canada dangerously exposed in an era of economic coercion. Andrew Coyne didn’t open with small talk. Speaking today at the CrossRoads Crop Conference in Edmonton, the Globe and Mail columnist said Canada is facing the “most serious economic and security crisis” of his lifetime — one that combines long-running domestic weaknesses with a rapidly shifting global order.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Building a Herd That Works: EPDs, Genomics and Smart Genetic Investments</title>
            <link>https://www.farms.com/news/building-a-herd-that-works-epds-genomics-and-smart-genetic-investments-237792.aspx</link>
            <guid>NEWS_237792</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 17:28:57 GMT</pubDate>
            <description>Julia and Robert operate a commercial cow-calf operation with a strong focus on making informed, strategic management and breeding decisions. They market all calves at weaning and have a goal to increase weaning weights by 20 pounds without sacrificing calving ease, which remains a key priority for both cow health and labour requirements.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Canola and Biofuels: Share Your Perspective</title>
            <link>https://www.farms.com/news/canola-and-biofuels-share-your-perspective-237791.aspx</link>
            <guid>NEWS_237791</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 17:27:31 GMT</pubDate>
            <description>Canola oil is an excellent feedstock for biofuel production, offering farmers an additional domestic market opportunity for their canola crop. The national and provincial canola grower associations have come together to deepen our understanding of canola farmers’ views and knowledge about the connections between canola and biofuels.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Quebec names Lori-Anne Berthiaume and Steeve Nadeau from Ferme Porc SB as Outstanding Young Farmers for 2026</title>
            <link>https://www.farms.com/news/quebec-names-lori-anne-berthiaume-and-steeve-nadeau-from-ferme-porc-sb-located-in-saint-elz-ar-as-their-outstanding-young-farmers-for-2026-237788.aspx</link>
            <guid>NEWS_237788</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 16:36:40 GMT</pubDate>
            <description>On January 13th, at the Congress Centre of St-Hyacinthe, Quebec’s Outstanding Young Farmers announced Lori-Anne Berthiaume and Steeve Nadeau as their regional winners with over 430 people in attendance. They will proudly represent Quebec at the National Event in Vancouver BC in November 2026.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Building Tomorrow’s Leaders: FCC 4-H Club Fund Supports Ontario Clubs</title>
            <link>https://www.farms.com/news/building-tomorrow-s-leaders-fcc-4-h-club-fund-supports-ontario-clubs-237787.aspx</link>
            <guid>NEWS_237787</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 16:35:23 GMT</pubDate>
            <description>Recipients of the 2025 FCC 4-H Club Fund have been announced!</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>APAS Calls for Impact Assessment in Wake of AAFC Cutbacks</title>
            <link>https://www.farms.com/news/apas-calls-for-impact-assessment-in-wake-of-aafc-cutbacks-237786.aspx</link>
            <guid>NEWS_237786</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 16:33:35 GMT</pubDate>
            <description>The Agricultural Producers Association of Saskatchewan (APAS) is sounding the alarm over Agriculture and Agri-Food Canada’s (AAFC) decision to close seven federal research sites and eliminate roughly 665 positions nationwide, warning the move could deal lasting damage to Canadian agriculture.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Bank of Canada Holds Rates; Warns on Trade, Geopolitical Risks</title>
            <link>https://www.farms.com/news/bank-of-canada-holds-rates-warns-on-trade-geopolitical-risks-237785.aspx</link>
            <guid>NEWS_237785</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 16:32:45 GMT</pubDate>
            <description>The Bank of Canada held its key overnight lending rate unchanged at 2.25% on Wednesday, maintaining borrowing costs for the second consecutive time as it warned on “unpredictable U.S. trade policies and geopolitical risks.”</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>AAFC cuts hitting seven research sites</title>
            <link>https://www.farms.com/ag-industry-news/aafc-cuts-hitting-seven-research-sites-784.aspx</link>
            <guid>NEWS_237784</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 14:05:02 GMT</pubDate>
            <description>Canada’s ag sector is expressing concern over the full scope of cuts coming to Agriculture and Agri-Food Canada.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Ag included in PM’s affordability measures</title>
            <link>https://www.farms.com/ag-industry-news/ag-included-in-pm-s-affordability-measures-783.aspx</link>
            <guid>NEWS_237783</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 14:02:04 GMT</pubDate>
            <description>Producers can fully write off some greenhouses.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Industry groups upset with status of E15</title>
            <link>https://www.farms.com/ag-industry-news/industry-groups-upset-with-status-of-e15-781.aspx</link>
            <guid>NEWS_237781</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 12:32:59 GMT</pubDate>
            <description>The House of Representatives removed E15 provisions from a funding package.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Minister MacDonald launches consultations for the Next Agricultural Policy Framework</title>
            <link>https://www.farms.com/news/minister-macdonald-launches-consultations-for-the-next-agricultural-policy-framework-237780.aspx</link>
            <guid>NEWS_237780</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 11:29:46 GMT</pubDate>
            <description>Ottawa, Ontario – Agriculture and Agri-Food Canada</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Cohort Wholesale strengthens partnership with Andermatt Canada</title>
            <link>https://www.farms.com/news/cohort-wholesale-strengthens-partnership-with-andermatt-canada-237779.aspx</link>
            <guid>NEWS_237779</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 11:28:14 GMT</pubDate>
            <description>Cohort Wholesale is advancing its partnership with Andermatt Canada, assuming the exclusive national distribution rights for Virosoft CP4, a trusted biological crop protection product in Andermatt’s global portfolio.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>OGVG supports federal affordability measures</title>
            <link>https://www.farms.com/news/ogvg-supports-federal-affordability-measures-237778.aspx</link>
            <guid>NEWS_237778</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 11:27:26 GMT</pubDate>
            <description>Ontario Greenhouse Vegetable Growers (OGVG) welcomes the January 26 announcement by Prime Minister Carney outlining new federal measures intended to make groceries and other essential goods more affordable for Canadians.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Global Crude Oil Tanker Rates Surge Then Ease in Early 2026</title>
            <link>https://www.farms.com/ag-industry-news/global-crude-oil-tanker-rates-surge-then-ease-in-early-2026-774.aspx</link>
            <guid>NEWS_237774</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 10:27:33 GMT</pubDate>
            <description>Crude oil tanker rates peaked in late 2025 due to strong demand and trade shifts before easing in early 2026 as seasonal shipping needs declined worldwide.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Canada Urges Action Against EU Grain Trade Barriers</title>
            <link>https://www.farms.com/ag-industry-news/canada-urges-action-against-eu-grain-trade-barriers-773.aspx</link>
            <guid>NEWS_237773</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 10:22:58 GMT</pubDate>
            <description>Canada Grains Council calls for stronger leadership to protect grain exports from EU trade barriers and promote science based agricultural regulations worldwide.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>How Farmers Can Manage Premiums Through Reviews Discounts</title>
            <link>https://www.farms.com/ag-industry-news/how-farmers-can-manage-premiums-through-reviews-discounts-772.aspx</link>
            <guid>NEWS_237772</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 10:15:04 GMT</pubDate>
            <description>Farm families can lower insurance costs by understanding premiums using discounts reviewing policies yearly and managing risks to reduce claims while protecting valuable farm assets.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>New High Yielding Oat Boosts market value</title>
            <link>https://www.farms.com/ag-industry-news/new-high-yielding-oat-boosts-market-value-771.aspx</link>
            <guid>NEWS_237771</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 10:10:23 GMT</pubDate>
            <description>The University of Minnesota introduces MN Amber a new oat variety delivering higher yields strong grain quality and disease resistance for food grade oat production nationwide.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>John Deere Enhances U.S. Supply Chain</title>
            <link>https://www.farms.com/ag-industry-news/john-deere-enhances-u-s-supply-chain-769.aspx</link>
            <guid>NEWS_237769</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 10:02:47 GMT</pubDate>
            <description>John Deere will open two new U.S. facilities, create hundreds of jobs and strengthen American manufacturing through expanded distribution and excavator production.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Agri Spray Drones and WinField United Partner</title>
            <link>https://www.farms.com/ag-industry-news/agri-spray-drones-and-winfield-united-partner-767.aspx</link>
            <guid>NEWS_237767</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 09:55:42 GMT</pubDate>
            <description>Agri Spray Drones and WinField United partners to expand education research and adoption of drone-based crop application systems across US agriculture.</description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>BCRC webinar recap: Early calf life survival</title>
            <link>https://www.farms.com/news/bcrc-webinar-recap-early-calf-life-survival-237766.aspx</link>
            <guid>NEWS_237766</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 09:52:34 GMT</pubDate>
            <description>The first 24 hours of a beef calf’s life are the most vulnerable. During the Beef Cattle Research Council’s webinar, Early Calf Life Survival, Dr. Roger Richard of Shoal Lake Veterinary Clinic, Dr. Claire Windeyer from University of Calgary Veterinary Medicine and Heidi Bennett with W.A. Ranches discussed navigating calving and the critical early life stages of beef calves to give them their best start.</description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>