<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Modern Farmer</title>
        <link>https://modernfarmer.com/</link>
        <description>Farm. Food. Life.</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 16:47:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <language>en-US</language>
        <generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.7.4</generator>
        <image>
            <url>https://modernfarmer.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/08/cropped-favicon-1-32x32.png</url>
            <title>Modern Farmer</title>
            <link>https://modernfarmer.com/</link>
            <width>32</width>
            <height>32</height>
        </image>
        <item>
            <title>Forest Farming: Why it Might Make Sense for Your Land</title>
            <link>https://modernfarmer.com/2026/01/forest-farming/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 10:00:36 +0000</pubDate>
            <category><![CDATA[Farm]]></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://modernfarmer.com/?p=168562</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Also called agroforestry, forest farming is a great way to work within your environmental parameters and utilize the tree canopy to produce more for your farm. Especially for those who live in forested areas, this practice enhances farm output without compromising the ecosystem.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://modernfarmer.com/2026/01/forest-farming/">Forest Farming: Why it Might Make Sense for Your Land</a> appeared first on <a href="https://modernfarmer.com">Modern Farmer</a>.</p>
]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The 9 Best Flowers and Vegetables to Winter Sow</title>
            <link>https://modernfarmer.com/2026/01/flowers-vegetables-winter-sow/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 14:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
            <category><![CDATA[Farm]]></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://modernfarmer.com/?p=168631</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>For farms in colder areas, starting seeds in time for the spring market requires a significant amount of time and indoor space. Winter sowing is a method that can be done outdoors and gives seedlings a stronger constitution as they mature. Here, we share plants that thrive when winter sown.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://modernfarmer.com/2026/01/flowers-vegetables-winter-sow/">The 9 Best Flowers and Vegetables to Winter Sow</a> appeared first on <a href="https://modernfarmer.com">Modern Farmer</a>.</p>
]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>5 Agri-Environmental Strategies that Prevent Species Loss</title>
            <link>https://modernfarmer.com/2026/01/agri-environmental-strategies/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 10:00:49 +0000</pubDate>
            <category><![CDATA[Farm]]></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://modernfarmer.com/?p=168488</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>On today’s farms, ecologically-friendly practices are on the rise. Using agri-environmental strategies, farmers prevent environmental degradation, preserving natural spaces and the species that live in them. </p>
<p>The post <a href="https://modernfarmer.com/2026/01/agri-environmental-strategies/">5 Agri-Environmental Strategies that Prevent Species Loss</a> appeared first on <a href="https://modernfarmer.com">Modern Farmer</a>.</p>
]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>The New Superfood With Minimal Environmental Footprint</title>
            <link>https://modernfarmer.com/2026/01/superfood-environmental-footprint/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 10:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
            <category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://modernfarmer.com/?p=168464</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>In the future, farmers can diversify the output of their farms with Chlorella vulgaris, a freshwater alga gaining traction as a dietary supplement and superfood with a minimal environmental footprint, most notably in Japan, Taiwan, and Germany. </p>
<p>The post <a href="https://modernfarmer.com/2026/01/superfood-environmental-footprint/">The New Superfood With Minimal Environmental Footprint</a> appeared first on <a href="https://modernfarmer.com">Modern Farmer</a>.</p>
]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Reconsidering Hemp: A Promising Grain Crop</title>
            <link>https://modernfarmer.com/2025/12/hemp-grain-crop/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 10:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
            <category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://modernfarmer.com/?p=168436</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Growing a hemp grain crop isn’t difficult, and its rising popularity makes it an interesting option for farmers. This high-value market item is a prolific plant with many uses. Diverging greatly from medicinal cannabis, cultivating fiber and grain hemp is a worthwhile endeavor.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://modernfarmer.com/2025/12/hemp-grain-crop/">Reconsidering Hemp: A Promising Grain Crop</a> appeared first on <a href="https://modernfarmer.com">Modern Farmer</a>.</p>
]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>7 Winter Storage Mistakes That Will Ruin Your Crops</title>
            <link>https://modernfarmer.com/2025/12/crop-winter-storage/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 10:00:09 +0000</pubDate>
            <category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://modernfarmer.com/?p=168396</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>As you pack away your equipment and store each crop for winter, avoid the common pitfalls that can ruin your efforts. </p>
<p>The post <a href="https://modernfarmer.com/2025/12/crop-winter-storage/">7 Winter Storage Mistakes That Will Ruin Your Crops</a> appeared first on <a href="https://modernfarmer.com">Modern Farmer</a>.</p>
]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>5 Simple Value-Added Products You Can Produce on the Farm in Winter</title>
            <link>https://modernfarmer.com/2025/12/winter-farm-products/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 10:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
            <category><![CDATA[Farm]]></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://modernfarmer.com/?p=168421</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>You can sell and produce winter farm products, even after the harvests stop. Adding a few high-value items to your to-do list provides revenue when most farms are shut down waiting for spring. Plan for a few next season and offset some of the costs farming presents.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://modernfarmer.com/2025/12/winter-farm-products/">5 Simple Value-Added Products You Can Produce on the Farm in Winter</a> appeared first on <a href="https://modernfarmer.com">Modern Farmer</a>.</p>
]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>What to Plant in Cold Frames and Hoop Houses in December</title>
            <link>https://modernfarmer.com/2025/12/december-cold-frame-hoop-house/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 10:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
            <category><![CDATA[Food]]></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://modernfarmer.com/?p=168378</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Your December cold frame, hoop house, or covered row produces all kinds of crops as long as you achieve the right internal temperature. Pop in cold-hardy crops and get ready to harvest throughout the chilly months. </p>
<p>The post <a href="https://modernfarmer.com/2025/12/december-cold-frame-hoop-house/">What to Plant in Cold Frames and Hoop Houses in December</a> appeared first on <a href="https://modernfarmer.com">Modern Farmer</a>.</p>
]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>How to Amend the Soil After Harvest (and Why You Should)</title>
            <link>https://modernfarmer.com/2025/11/amend-soil-after-harvest/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 10:00:56 +0000</pubDate>
            <category><![CDATA[Farm]]></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://modernfarmer.com/?p=168358</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>It makes sense to amend soil after harvest, especially in the fall. This is when most farms and gardens are about to shut down for the year, awaiting spring’s warmth. During the winter, soil amendments have an opportunity to break down and become fully part of the soil.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://modernfarmer.com/2025/11/amend-soil-after-harvest/">How to Amend the Soil After Harvest (and Why You Should)</a> appeared first on <a href="https://modernfarmer.com">Modern Farmer</a>.</p>
]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>How to Get Started With Regenerative Grazing: 5 Recommendations</title>
            <link>https://modernfarmer.com/2025/11/regenerative-grazing/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 10:00:51 +0000</pubDate>
            <category><![CDATA[Farm]]></category>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://modernfarmer.com/?p=168338</guid>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>If you’re a rancher who wants to work toward a regenerative pasture model, you don’t have to do it all at once. Instead, focus on a few small, simple steps. You’ll be working a regenerative grazing operation in due time.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://modernfarmer.com/2025/11/regenerative-grazing/">How to Get Started With Regenerative Grazing: 5 Recommendations</a> appeared first on <a href="https://modernfarmer.com">Modern Farmer</a>.</p>
]]></description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>